Contact

john.winko@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/john-winko (LinkedIn) www.johnwinko.com (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Joint Military Operations
Active DoD Secret Clearance
Military Leadership

John Winko

Course Instructor at US Navy

Greater Chicago Area

Summary

20 year US Navy veteran. I am currently a naval instructor for basic engineering theory but have also taught a diverse area of subjects ranging from basic water survival skills and small boat operations to office automation and curriculum gamification.

My future goals are to pursue further advanced education in the technology and game development sectors while seeking experience and employment developing learning products that further immerse and more effectively train people for the challenges of tomorrow.

Experience

US Navy

19 years 11 months

Senior Instructor

March 2019 - Present (2 years 8 months)

North Chicago, Illinois, United States

- Taught basic engineering skills and shipboard familiarity to accession level Sailors.
- Recertified as a Master Training Specialist.
- Generated lesson plans and supplemental materials for over 100 engineering topics covering 190 instructional hours of material.
- Advised on future curriculum modalities and benchmarks.

Engineering Supervisor

February 2016 - March 2019 (3 years 2 months)

Leonardo, New Jersey, United States

- Supervised 8 personnel in the maintenance, operation and repairs of Harbor Security Boats, Oil Spill Response Craft and Harbor Operations Equipment.
- Authored a written technical report for service specific maintenance requirements and procedures for Yamaha and Honda outboard engines.
- Advised regionally on initiatives to improve maintenance effectiveness and emergency response tactics.

Survival Instructor

January 2013 - February 2016 (3 years 2 months)

North Chicago, Illinois, United States

- Led 37 civilian and military instructors across 2 shifts in the initial swim qualification and remediation of over 120,000 recruits.
- Qualified as Master Training Specialist
- Redesigned and normalized the legal (RLSO) database. Hardened electronic security policy and integrated with MS Office products for form letter and report generation.
- Member of Command Training Team, provided workshops on topics including sexual harassment, workplace diversity, suicide awareness and equal opportunity.

Machinist Mate

December 2009 - January 2013 (3 years 2 months)

Bangor Base, Washington, United States

Machinist Mate

October 2006 - December 2009 (3 years 3 months)

Jacksonville, Florida, United States

Machinist Mate

February 2002 - October 2006 (4 years 9 months)

Charleston, South Carolina Metropolitan Area

Trainee

December 2001 - February 2002 (3 months)

Great Lakes, Illinois, United States

City of Jacksonville

Lifeguard

June 1997 - September 2000 (3 years 4 months)

Jacksonville, Florida, United States

Education

Capella University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Information Technology · (January 2012 - November 2014)

Florida State College at Jacksonville

Associate of Arts - AA, General Studies · (September 2009 - June 2011)